# **DEBRA WILKIE**

# 813-727-7801 | debrapwilkie@gmail.com | linkedin.com/in/debra-wilkie

### **Profile**

Experienced leader of cross-functional teams utilizing Agile/Scrum skills and analytical abilities to plan, build and launch products. Excellent problem solver who enjoys learning, exploring, and diving-in to a project and looks forward to applying strategic planning skills and leadership abilities to solving the next challenge.

### **Highlights**

- Strategic Planning
- Communication/Presentations
- Agile/Scrum Methodologies
- Test-Driven Development
- User Story Creation
- Functional Backend and UI Testing
- Analytical Skills
- Ingestion and User Logging
- Product Documentation

### **Professional Experience**

## GE / Belcan | Wilmington, NC Project Manager

July 2018 - Present

- Developing, testing and implementing a new software application for an American Fortune 100 energy company in collaboration with GE
- Communicating with clients to discuss design needs and organize project requirements according to a value based level of priorities
- Building credibility, establishing rapport and maintaining a high degree of client satisfaction by timely responding to ongoing software support and training
- Leading and collaborating with development team using Agile methods to discuss and design software applications including daily standup meetings, design sessions, user story creation via CA Rally
- Trouble shooting and debugging skills including creating functional backend and UI tests to address potential software defects
- Drafting and delivering over 20+ pages of product documentation in Confluence with varied content for use with new team members, client explanations of value, technical coding dictionaries, and product marketing
- Collaborating with data scientists and other project managers to implement new reporting structures via Excel and Tableau for stakeholder meetings increasing the efficiency in reporting and data reliability

## Bell Shoals Baptist Church | Brandon, FL Website Redesign Project Manager and Database Administrator

January 2016 – June 2017

- Developed and deployed updated Bell Shoals Academy website
  - o Discussed with client (Headmaster) the design needs
  - Conducted market research to assess current requirements and trends
  - Created project timeline to meet objectives
  - Vetted and hired companies to integrate required technologies seamlessly into overall project
  - o Conducted product testing with select feedback group (teachers, parents) and implemented changes
  - Deployed website utilizing SEO
- Improved processes for data retrieval and analysis and resolved problems and after switch from Shelby to Ministry Platform database system for a 5-campus church
- Improved database queries for creation of new classes as well as registration for continuing classes with 300+ students
- Created SQL database notifications to email appropriate contact of new registrations and required tasks
- Created Excel presentation from SQL queries to analyze the potential for a new church campus site
- Coded new HTML website/database skin to incorporate online payment portal and database account management for church events including mission trip purchase histories
- Integrated new website platforms including Church Online platform for live web streaming and RightNow Media

# **DEBRA WILKIE**

# 813-727-7801 | debrapwilkie@gmail.com | linkedin.com/in/debra-wilkie

# Parris Island Officer Spouses Club | Parris Island, SC Philanthropy Officer and Website Manager

May 2013 – May 2015

- Coordinated 3 volunteer projects, collaborated with various agencies for distribution and contacted businesses for auction donations
- Created advertisements for the auction on websites and newspapers, as well as distributing flyers
- Organization of guest registration, auction check out, and overall guest experience to ensure successful event
- Ensuring donor retention by writing personal notes of thanks and updating donation logs
- Web Manager; researched, designed, modified and maintained website
- Highly self-motivated with the ability to quickly learn and utilize innovative technologies

# **Technical College of the Lowcountry | Beaufort, SC Adjunct Professor**

May 2012 - Present

- Independently created and organized courses utilizing Blackboard's online learning management system
- Integrated learning objectives with the instructional materials utilizing multiple technologies to enhance learner interaction and usability
- Redesigned and taught a Music Appreciation Course in a 16 week on campus format as well a 10, 8, and 7 week online course
- Highly developed verbal skills with the ability to develop written directives and present material through PowerPoints, lectures and active discussions
- Resolved conflicts with students regarding grade disputes utilizing the academic policies

### University of Tampa | Tampa, FL Adjunct Professor of Voice

August 2008 - May 2011

- Ensured that learning objectives and course requirements were understood and developed supplemental resources to enhance knowledge
- Identified a possible curriculum addition and created and presented recommendations to department chair
- Collaborated with colleague to refine and create the course curriculum
- Implemented recommended changes in a timely fashion which resulted in 2 new classes added to the schedule

### **Education**

### Computer Science BS, Post-Baccalaureate

Oregon State University | eCampus

#### **Bachelor of Music & Master of Music**

Indiana University | Bloomington, IN

#### Skills

- Computer Skills: MS Office (Excel), Windows and Apple OS
- Computer Programming Skills: HTML, Node.js, PHP, Python, SQL
- Computer Technologies: Android Studio, GitHub, Linux, Tableau
- Learning Management Systems: Blackboard, Canvas, Edsby, Google Classroom

### **Volunteer Highlights**

- Topsail High School; School Improvement Team (Parent Representative)
- Scotts Hill Baptist Church; Production Team Computer Graphics/Lyrics (Volunteer)
- Habitat for Humanity (Volunteer)